# Tyler J. Roberts

(262)388-4050 | tjroberts<br/>314@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyleroberts | https://github.com/tyler314

## Summary

Software engineer with 6+ years experience in development and design. My most recent work has been well-balanced between building back-end systems, and front-end web applications.

Skills: agile, amazon web services (aws), api, ci/cd pipelines, css, databases, docker, express, git, grafana, html, java, javascript, jira, kafka, kotlin, kubernetes, linux, nodejs, project management, python, reactjs, scrum, seo, sql, typescript, version control

## Experience

### Software Engineer & Project Manager

Copper + Honey Salon  $\cdot$  Freelance

Feb  $2023 - Present \cdot Remote$ 

- https://www.copperandhoneysalon.com
- Designed fully functional website from scratch, using AWS tools to quickly launch in time for the client's grand opening.
- Leveraged SEO techniques resulting in the website rising to the top Google Search results for hair extensions in the local area. Consistently receiving 300+ clicks/month.
- Designed solution for clients to edit their employee info on their site at any time, seamlessly working across all screen sizes.
- Work directly with the owners and an independent UX Designer, in order to design software solutions, create timelines, and conduct demos.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Javascript, React.js, Material UI, SEO.

### Software Engineer

#### Warner Bros. Discovery · Contract

 $Mar 2023 - Dec 2023 \cdot Remote$ 

- Became key team contributor within first month by quickly becoming a part of on-call rotations, contributing to code reviews, and pushing code, allowing our team to meet the MAX launch deadline in May.
- Led efforts of designing novel integration tests, and setting up new Grafana monitoring + alerts for the team's new MAX services, in order to meet company SLA requirements.
- Lead engineer tasked with onboarding a new service from a re-org. Required collaboration with three away teams, to understand the service and get it running before my contract's end.
- $\ \, General\ \, Operational\ \, Excellence.\ \, Ran\ \, load\ \, tests,\ \, contributed\ \, to\ \, new\ \, documentation,\ \, scrum\ \, leader,\ \, etc.$
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Typescript, Node.js, Express.js, Kafka, Grafana, Kubernetes + Docker

## Software Engineer

#### Amazon.com · Full-Time

Dec 2019 – Jan 2023 · Seattle, WA

- Designed adapted responses for Smart Home requests. Features such as sharing customer insights, listing device capabilities, and a "Good Morning / Night" experience.
- Delivered Brief / Verbose Mode for ACMS. Developed filtering logic to serve personalized responses based on the individual customer's device setting.
- Migrated all Alexa personality content from a legacy CMS, to ACMS/ARMS. Three month endeavor that required the development of bulk migration scripts, working closely with a select few engineers, PMs, and content creators across all supported locales.
- Led the org in hiring engineers by conducting over 50 interviews in Q1 2022, resulting in a higher head count for hiring. Received the quarterly award for this effort.
- Social chair for the org, responsible for organizing quarterly events during the pandemic remote period, encouraging teammates to socialize and get to know each other better.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Kotlin, Javascript, React.js, CI/CD Code Pipelines, Git

#### Education

B.S. Computer Engineering, Computer Science, & Mathematics with Physics Certificate (minor). University of Wisconsin - Madison, May 2017